

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







CSM, ITIL Lead Business Analyst seeking roles in IT Project Management, Delivery Management, Requirement Gathering, Business Analysis, Solution Design, Process Automation, Operational Excellence, Axure Requisite Pro



Total Experience: 11 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MBAPGDM [Finance, Operations,IT]

Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Designation: Lead Business Analyst -IT

Current Company: Newgen Software Technologies Ltd.,

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: Anywhere in North India, Anywhere in South India. Anywhere in West India

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Business Analyst

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Lead Business Analyst,IT Project Management,Delivery Management,Requirement Gathering,Business Analysis,Solution Design,Process Automation,Operational Excellence,HTML,Axure Requisite Pro,Rational Rose

Verified : Le Phone Number | Email - id

Last Modified: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills | Work Authorization

Summary

Competent professional with nearly 11 years of rich experience in business analysis / project operations with key focus on top line profitability while ensuring optimal utilization of resources by making optimum use of qualitative and quantitative analysis tools

Experience of working in the domain of Banking and Financial Services; implemented BPM and ECM Addressed expectations of the product, conducted analysis, created functionalities & features in interaction with client Strong acumen in organizing, analysing, synthesizing and/or summarizing data using appropriate methodologies Keen analyst with excellence in gathering and understanding requirements of clients & other multiple stakeholders (at strategic and tactical levels), followed by translation into functional specifications as well as provisioning of suitable solutions Analysed company performances, conducted benchmarking study/ trend analysis and used various business tools to assist the critical decision-making process

Work Experience

Newgen Software Technologies Ltd., as Lead Business Analyst -IT Mar 2015 to Till Date

Key Result Areas

Executing BPM, ECM, performing end-to-end requirement gathering, project sign-off, UAT testing and project delivery Managing implementation of process of Commercial Loan Origination, Collections, Consumer Loans Origination, Mobility and Legal Compliance System using BPM

Tata Consultancy Services as Systems Analyst Apr 2013 to Mar 2015

Key Result Areas:

Performed on client site on e-governance project, worked on gathering client requirements for preparation of functional requirement specifications and system requirement specifications documents

Steered the preparation of test cases, unit testing, sanity testing and managed preparation of reports & dashboards in MS using OBIEE

Hands-on knowledge of SQL and tools like MS-Visio, Axure RP, J-Developer and BI Publisher

Tata Consultancy Services as Assistant System Engineer Jul 2008 to Apr 2011

Key Result Areas:

Performed in group setting for Stolt Neilson Transportation Company, offered facets of computer support such as troubleshooting, installations & maintenance, adhering to ITIL process

Extensive knowledge in software packages and operating systems like Active Directory, Windows XP, Windows Server 2003, Outlook Exchange, AS400, Citrix and managed compilation

Generated reports of team, prepared service reports, technical charts, reports, collaborated with higher authorities and managed specific zones of APAC, EMEA and AMERICS as lead for Global Client

1

Important

Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E (Electrical and Electronics Engineering) from Manipal Institute of Technology in 2008 PG: MBA/PGDM (Finance, Operations,IT) from ICFAI Business School, Hyderabad in 2013

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
C++, Java			
MS-Office, MS-Visio, MS-Project			
Rational Rose,Requsite Pro,SAS,R			
Windows Server 2003,AS400,Citrix			
Active Directory, Axure and OBI			
OmniFlow, OmniDoc			
HTML		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
JavaScript		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
BPM		0	7 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Urdu	Beginner	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Category: General US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Physically Challenged: No

Countries: India
Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.